Guide to the PricewaterhouseCoopers Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Price Waterhouse Series I: Cataloged Documents
  - Subseries I.4: George O. May Files
    - Sub-subseries I.4.1: Arranged Correspondence
      - Fernald, H. B.; Herrick, Anson.; Hunt, Bishop C.; Paul, Randolph E.; Sanders, T. H.; Gay, Edwin F. Taxation, 1940-1942 (1-2) (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Alvord, Ellsworth.; Bauer, Charles C.; Bond, Henry Herrick.; Burgess, W. Randolph.; Magill, Roswell.; Tarleau, Thomas N. Taxation, 1942 (3-9) (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Willits, Joseph H.; Noyes, C. Reinhold; Paul, Randolph E.; Schieffelin, William J.; Seligman, Eustace.; Stam, Colin F.; Stewart, Walter W.; Taxation, 1942 (10-16) (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Bankes, R. W.; Elliott, C. F.; Friedman, Elisha M.; Gerard, Sumner.; Hunt, Bishop C.; Lombard, Norman; Montgomery, Robert H.; Sanders, Thomas H.; Chester, Phil C.; Lappen, Chester; Neal, Phil C.; Harvard University Taxation, 1943-1944 (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Austin, Maurice; Hayes, James H.; Rosenberg, Maurice; Sloan, George A.; Ballantine, Arthur A.; Brundage, Percival F.; Garretson, James.; Sanders, Thomas H.; Taxation, 1945-1947 (1-2) (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Burling, Edward B.; Dalupan, F.; Oliver, J. W.; Ashbaugh, W. L.; Austin, Maurice; Carey, John L.; Gale, Frank; Green, Edward; Hagerty, Harry C.; Merz, Charles; Spencer, M. C.; New York Times. Taxation, 1947 (3-13) (Box 71, Folder 6)
      - Ballantine, Arthur A.; Brach, Henry.; Lasser, J. K.; Staiger, Carl R.; Carey, John L; Davis, John W. Taxation, 1948-1949 (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Blair, Edwin Foster.; Stam, Colin F.; Doughton, Robert L.; Folsom, Marion B.; Gradwohl, Richard G.; Schwulst, Earl B.; Taxation, 1950-1952 (Box 71, Folder 8)
      - Angell, Montgomery B.; Cannon, Arthur M.; Mills, Leslie; Larsen, Roy; May, George O.; Griswold, Erwin N.; American Law Institute. Taxation, 1953 (Box 71, Folder 9)
      - Blough, Carman G.; Carey, John L.; Grady, Paul R.; Magill, Roswell.; Richardson, Mark E.; Seidman, J. S.; David, Donald K.; Douglas, Thornton G.; Howitt, Harold; Inglis, John B.; Mills, Leslie; Tarleau, Thomas M.; Taxation, 1954 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      - Bator, Paul M.; Cary, William L.; du Pre, Derek.; Griswold, Erwin N.; Jack, Robert L.; Mills, Leslie; Olfson, Herbert B.; Seidman, J. S.; Armory, Robert; Curtis, John T.; Knauth, Oswald W.; Knauth, Oswald.; Mills, Wilbur D.; Reeves, William; Tarleau, Thomas M.; Taxation, 1955-1956 (1-6) (Box 71, Folder 11)
      - Mills, Leslie; Burns, Arthur; Cannon, Arthur M.; Demarest, Rosemary; Taxation, 1956 (7-16) (Box 71, Folder 12)
      - Brundage, Percival F.; Burns, James M.; Egger, Roscoe L.; Herz, Theodore.; Blum, John B.; Fabricant, Solomon; Hunt, Bishop C.; Simonetti, Gilbert.; Taxation, 1957-1961 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Taxation-Canada, 1949 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      - Robson, Thomas B.; Demarest, Rosemary Price Waterhouse &Co., London. Taxation-Great Britain, 1949-1954 (Box 72, Folder 3)
      - Dohr, James L.; Staub, Walter A. Temporary National Economic Committee, 1941 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      - Shimizu, Souichi Macmillan Company. Translating and Interpreting, 1955 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      - Ballantine, Arthur.; Elliston, H. B.; Gerry, Peter G.; Sapienza, John T.; Bacon, Robert L.; Blum, John Morton; Dillon, ClarenceSchlesinger, Arthur M.; Undistributed Profits Tax, 1936-1960 (Box 72, Folder 6)
      - Greene, A. Crawford.; Millett, John D.; Ogden, W. B.; Olive, George S.; Swindell, L. I.; Thomas, Marshall M.; Andersen, Arthur Ernst Franke, North, Hannon Haskins Scovell, Wellington Peat, Marwick, Mitchell Lybrand, Ross Bros. Price Waterhouse Commission On Financing Higher Education. Universities and Colleges-Accounting, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 7)
      - Epstein, Ralph C. US Census Bureau, 1934 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      - Marrinan, John US Senate-Committee on Banking and Currency, 1933 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      - Roswell, David S. US Steel Corporation (Keyes, John Maynard), 1940 (Box 72, Folder 10)
      - Burgess, W. Randolph.; Roswell, David S.; US Treasury Department, 1936-1954 (Box 72, Folder 11)
      - Davis, John W.; Hatfield, Henry R.; Moore, Hoyt A.; Berger, R. O.; Clark, Charles E.; Demarest, Rosemary; Gordon, Myron J.; Waterhouse, Nicholas; Valuation, 1941-1954 (Box 72, Folder 12)
      - War Contract Settlement Program, 1947 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      - Rathbone, Albert; Blackett, Basil; Moulton, H. G.; Winston, Garrard B.; War Loans, 1922-1936 (Box 72, Folder 14)
      - War Losses, 1945 (Box 72, Folder 15)
      - Fletcher, M. L.; Clay, Henry Wartime Accounting, 1941-1945 (Box 72, Folder 16)
      - Pearson, Russel A. Washington Society of CPA's, 1956 (Box 72, Folder 17)
      - Finletter, Thomas K. Woodrow Wilson Foundation, 1947 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Subseries I.5: Chronological Correspondence
    Incoming and outgoing business correspondence, filed in reverse chronological order.
    - , 1919 - 1920 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - , 1921 - 1922 (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - , 1923 (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - , 1924 (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - , 1925 - 1926 (Box 72, Folder 23)
    - , 1927 (Box 72, Folder 24)
    - , 1928 (Box 72, Folder 25)
    - , 1929 (Box 72, Folder 26)
    - , 1930 - 1949 (Box 72, Folder 27)
    - , 1950 - 1953 (Box 72, Folder 28)
    - , 1954 - 1956 (Box 72, Folder 29)
    - , 1957 (Box 72, Folder 30)
    - , 1958 (Box 72, Folder 31)
    - , 1959 (Box 72, Folder 32)
    - , 1960 (Box 72, Folder 33)
    - , 1961 (Box 72, Folder 34)
  - Subseries I.6: Drafts and Notes
    Accounting history and biographical material, largely uncompleted. - Typescripts with handwritten notes. Arranged Chronologically. Each draft is preceded by a top card handwritten by researcher with suggested subject headings.
    - Sub-subseries I.6.1: Notes
      - Topics Include: Accountancy, Accounting Philosophy, Accounting History, Taxation, 1920s -1955 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Articles for Harvard Law Review. Topics include: Accounting Law, Accounting Principles and Standards, History of Taxation, Business Income, Income Taxes, Internal Revenue Code of 1954, Jan. - Feb. 1956 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Mostly drafts of Seattle lectures and subsequent book, based on these lectures. Topics include: AIA-CAP, AIA Committee on cooperation with Stock Exchange, Accountancy, Accounting Principles and Standards, Accounting Terminology, Business Corporation, Depreciation, History of Accounting, Income, Income Taxes, Intangible Assets, Inventories, R&D costs, Pensions, Public Utilities, Regulatory accounting, Taxation, USSEC, Auditors Reports and Certificate, May Biography, 1956 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Mostly drafts of Seattle lectures and subsequent book, based on these lectures. Topics include: AIA-CAP, AIA Committee on cooperation with Stock Exchange, Accounting History,Accounting Principles and Standards, Accounting Terminology, Depreciation, Inflation, Income, Intangible Assets, Pension Plans, Price Level Accounting, Public Utilities, Railroad accounting, Taxation, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      - Topics Include: AIA-CAP, AIA Committee on cooperation with Stock Exchange, Accountancy, Accounting Principles and Standards, Auditor's Report, Depreciation, Financial Accounting, Price Level Accounting, Public Utilities, Railroad Accounting, Regulated Accounting, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      - AIA Committee on cooperation with Stock Exchange, Accounting Education, Business Income, Depreciation, Harvard University, Income, Replacement Cost, Spacek, Study Group on Business Income, 1958 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      - Topics include: Accounting Principles and Standards, Accounting Research Bulletins, Accounting History, AIA-CAP and AIA-ABP, Committee on Cooperation with Stock Exchange, USSEC, Inventories, Depreciation, Public Utitlities, Income taxation, Study Group on Business Income, Jornal of Accountancy, Price level accounting, 1959 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      - Topics include: May - Biography, History of Accountancy, Accounting Principles and Standards, AIA-CAP and AIA-ABP, Committee on Cooperation with Stock Exchange, Inventories, Depreciation, International Congress of Accountants (1904), Layers and Accountants, Public Utitlities, Income taxes, AICPA, Securities Act of 1933, Securities Exchange Act of 1934, Auditing, Earnings, USSEC, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      - Topics include: Accounting Principles and Standards, Taxation, Auditing, Inventories, Depreciation, USSEC, AIA, Study Group on Business Income, Committee on Cooperation with Stock Exchange, Committee on Terminology, AICPA, Financial Accounting, Railroad Accounting, Income Taxes, Public Utilities, Regulatory Commissions, Corporate Excise Tax, Inventories, Cost, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      - Subjects include: AIA Committee on cooperation with Stock Exchange, Accounting Education, Accounting Principles and Standards, Auditor's Report and Certificates, Earnings, Income, Depreciation, Price level accounting, Taxation, Undistributed Profits Tax, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Sub-subseries I.6.2: Subject Files
      Alphabetical by subject
      - AIA, 1948 - 1956 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      - AICPA - Leopold Spacek, 1957 - 1959 (Box 73, Folder 12)
      - Columbia University Accountants - Education and Training, 1948 - 1959 (Box 73, Folder 13)
      - Accountants - Education and Training (various schools), 1952 - 1959 (Box 73, Folder 14)
      - Accounting Research, [1956] (Box 73, Folder 15)
      - American Statistical Association, 1937 - 1938 (Box 73, Folder 16)
      - American Statistical Association, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 17)
      - Bureau of Internal Revenue - Miscellaneous Taxation, 1921 - 1927 (Box 73, Folder 18)
      - Congressional Committee on Internal Revenue Taxation, Apr. - Sep. 1927 (Box 73, Folder 19)
      - Congressional Committee on Internal Revenue Taxation, Octr. - Nov. 1927 (Box 73, Folder 20)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, 1937 (Box 73, Folder 21)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, 1938 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, 1942 - 1943 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      - Council on Foreign Relations, 1951 - 1953 (Box 74, Folder 3)
      - Depreciation, 1925 - 1959 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Du Pont, 1948 (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Financial Accounting, 1956 - 1959 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - International Chamber of Commerce - Double Taxation, 1923 - 1929 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - Inventories - Last-in First-out Method, 1948 - 1953 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Journal of Accountancy, 1954 - 1957 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - League of Nations - Double Taxation, May 1926 (Box 74, Folder 10 - 11)
      - League of Nations - Double Taxation, Nov. 1926 - Feb. 1927 (Box 74, Folder 12)
      - George O. May May Biography, 1936 - 1949 (Box 74, Folder 13)
      - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1954 (Box 74, Folder 14)
      - Museum of Science, Art and Industry, 1959 (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1935 - 1936 (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1939 - 1950 (Box 74, Folder 17)
      - New York Times, Oct. - Dec. 1959 (Box 74, Folder 18)
      - Pensions, 1949 - 1950 (Box 74, Folder 19)
      - Philadelphia Transportation Company Case, 1958 - 1960 (Box 74, Folder 20)
      - Price Waterhouse - History, 1957 (Box 74, Folder 21)
      - Price Waterhouse - Library, 1949 - 1960 (Box 74, Folder 22)
      - Railroads, 1929 - 1960 (Box 74, Folder 23)
      - SEC, 1936 - 1961 (Box 74, Folder 24)
      - Study Group on Business Income, 1947 (Box 74, Folder 25)
      - Study Group on Business Income, 1948 (Box 74, Folder 26)
      - Study Group on Business Income, 1949 - Apr. 1950 (Box 74, Folder 27)
      - Study Group on Business Income, May - Dec. 1950 (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Study Group on Business Income, 1951 (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - Study Group on Business Income, 1951 - 1959 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      - Taxation, 1948 - 1959 (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - US Shipbuilding Company, 1956 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Sub-subseries I.6.3: Miscellaneous
      - Clippings, 1947 - 1959 (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Exerpts and Quotations (Box 75, Folder 7)
      - May Compilation on Depreciation, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 8)
      - Bailey, George D.; Blough, Carman G.; Grady, Paul; Kraaeyenhof, J; Leibling, Herman I.; Littleton, A. C.; Paton, W. A.; Penney, Louis H.; Powell, Weldon Articles by others. Topics include: AIA-CAP, AICPA, Accounting Principles and Standards, Accounting Terminology, Accounting Research, Cost, Financial Accounting, Capital Gains, Income, Inflation, Inventories, Depreciation, Matching Concept, Oil Industry, Pensions, Price Level Accounting, Property Values, Public Utilities, Railroad accounting, Replacement Costs, Study Group on Business Income, Taxation, 1948 - 1959 (Box 75, Folder 9)
      - Notebooks, n.d. (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Subseries I.7: Herman Bevis Files
    Herman W. Bevis lead Price Waterhouse &Co. in 1961 -1969 as a senior partner and the Executive Committee chairman, commited to the visible role in professional affairs. Bevis spent his entire career in New York office, admitted to partnership in 1946.
    - Sub-subseries I.7.1: Arranged Correspondence
      Includes memoranda and speeches attached and relating to the correspondence
      - Herman W. Bevis Correspondence, 1947 - 1957 (Box 75, Folder 11)
        [Includes undated]
      - Correspondence, 1958 - 1962 (Box 75, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence, 1963 - 1965 (Box 75, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence, 1966 - 1969 (Box 75, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1970 - 1977 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Sub-subseries I.7.2: Writings
      - Bevis Notebooks, 1970 - 1976 (Box 75, Folder 16)
      - Articles by Bevis: Current Costing - A Problem, Trends in Utility Accounting and Financing, Report on Pension Study, The Recent Reexamination of the Methods of Preparing for the Accounting Profession in the US, The Firm's Public Relations Council, Financing the Reputation of PW, Southwestern and an Auditor, US Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, Setting Accounting Standards - A job for thr Public or Private Sector, etc., 1946 - 1969 (Box 75, Folder 17)
      - Articles by other authors, 1962 - 1975 (Box 75, Folder 18)
        [Arranged alphabetically by author]
      - Miscellaneous notes, maps and spreadsheets (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Sub-subseries I.7.3: Subject Files
      - Accounting Bibliography, 1972 - 1975 (Box 75, Folder 20)
      - AICPA Accounting Principles Board - Essays and minutes, 1962 - 1969 (Box 75, Folder 21)
      - Banking and Securities Industru Committee BASIC: drafts, assets, leases, related correspondence, 1970 - 1975 (Box 76, Folder 1)
        [Herman Bevis was BASIC executive director]
      - Banking and Securities Industru Committee BASIC payments with enclosed correspondence, 1970 - 1974 (Box 76, Folder 2)
      - Bevis Business Travel, 1957 - 1977 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Bevis Personal Information, 1952 - 1975 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Depository Trust Company, Dec. 1981 - Oct. 1982, Printed Material) (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Employment quality and Incentives, 1972 - 1976 (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Environmental Regulations, 1972 - 1978 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Experience Evaluation Questioneers, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 8)
      - General Accounting Office GAO Materials, 1973 - 1982 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      - Human Resources Accounting, 1967 - 1975 (Box 76, Folder 10)
      - Human Resources - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1972 - 1975 (Box 76, Folder 11)
      - Memorandum Account Plan Materials, 1957 - 1969 (Box 76, Folder 12)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1948 - 1975 (Box 76, Folder 13)
      - Phone Directories, 1971 -1974 (Box 76, Folder 14)
      - Power of Attorney for PW (Box 76, Folder 15)
      - PW Articles of Partnership, 1944 - 1962 (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - PW Partner Admissions Analysis, 1939 - 1945 (Box 76, Folder 17)
      - PW Publications: 1971 Annual Report, Executive Letters, 1971 - 1983 (Box 76, Folder 18)
      - Signatures of Partners and Principals, 1957 (Box 76, Folder 19)
      - Special Car Associates: Railroad club car / luxury bus for executives commuting from CT to NYC, 1969 - 1979 (Box 76, Folder 20)
      - Special Car Associates - Financial Statement (Box 76, Folder 21)
      - Special Car Associates - Minutes of Meetings and Correspondence, 1971 - 1976 (Box 76, Folder 22)
      - Various Printed Materials, 1968 - 1982 (Box 76, Folder 23)
  - Subseries I.8: Centennial Research
    Conducted by Withrop group in 1988-1990 for book Accounting for Success.
    - Sub-subseries I.8.1: George O. May files
      Photocopies of selected correspondence with manuscript notes by researcher. In loose chronological order
      - Lewis D. Jones; William J. Caesar PW American Agency; Jones, Caesar &Co. General Correspondence, 1890-1900, 1890-1900 (Box 77, Folder 1 - 3)
        [Includes P&L reports and internal publications ]
      - PW American Agency; Jones, Caesar Dickinson, Wilmot &Sterrett General Correspondence, 1901-1911 (Box 77, Folder 4-5)
        [Includes reports and internal publications ]
      - Minutes of Partners' Meetings; Minutes of Partners' and Managers' Meetings, New York, Chicago, 1903 - 1940 (Box 77, Folder 6-7)
      - Articles of partnership, 1920-1959 (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - PW Partnership history, papers and agreements, 1901-1959 (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - PW Accountancy Issues, 1911-1960. Articles by George O. May: Professional Training Classes. Introductory Lecture - 1921, The Tax Maze- 1915, Qualifications in Certificates- 1915; Article by Arthur L. Dickinson: Accounting Practice and Procedure- 1913; Article by A. P. Richardson: National Aspects of Public Accountancy- 1915; Accountants' Index: 1920 / 1936-1939 / 1940-1943; Alden Smith: PW - An International Firm- 1957, 1911-1960 (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - PW, Gas &Electric Co., International Mercantile Marine Co.; N.Y. New Haven &Hartford Railroad; The Mines Finance Company; W. R. Grace &Co. PW history- 1902-1911: correspondence; Articles by G. O. May: Premiums and Discounts- 1906 and Accountants Confer with Insurance Commissioners- 1906; Accounts and audit reports for various clients- 1903-1908; Systems Reports - 1906; Automobile Journals - 1907, 1902 - 1911 (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - PW History - 1930-1939: Correspondence; Clients and prospective clients; Clippings on Joseph E. Sterrett (1927-1934), 1930 - 1939 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Notes from General Letter Book of Jones, Caesar, 1890-1899, Manuscript notes) (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - PW Reports: Business Research Committee - 1954; Development of LIFO Method - 1952; 1952-1954 (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - George O. May drafts - Uncatalogued Section, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, clippings and articles by George O. May with indices and notes by researcher; A. A. Berle, Jr. - Accounting and the law- 1937; 1930-1961 (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - Bureau of Internal Revenue Memorandum - 1927, 1927 (Box 77, Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence; Article by George O. May: Authoritative Financial Accounting- 1946; Proceedings of the 15th Annual Michigan Accounting Conference - 1939, 1931-1956 (Box 77, Folder 18)
      - G. O. May, Comprehensive Statement of Accounting Principles and Standards- drafts, 1959-1960 (Box 77, Folder 19)
      - Eastman Kodak; American Association of Public Accountants; Equitable Life Assurance Society Clients' reports, correspondence, American Association of Public Accountants Materials, 1902-1909 (Box 77, Folder 20)
      - PW Office Manuals - (1925), 1925, Photocopies) (Box 78, Folder 1)
        [Bound printed copies separated]
      - Lord &Taylor Works by G. O. May :Memoirs and Accounting Thoughts; Chronological List of Published Articles, Treatment of Repairs, Renewals and Improvements on Buildings, Plants and Machinery, autobiography; Office Organization Items - (1907-1910); Report on Lord &Taylor - (1909-1910); A. L. Dickinson: Duties and Responsibilities of the Public Accountant- 1902; 1902-1910 (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Time Lines (1845-1985); (1845-1963); Committees' Minutes (Executive Committee / Policy Committee / Policy Board, etc. - 1974-1987), 1974-1988 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Bibliography: Reader's Guide to Periodical Literature - (1890-1924); International Guide to Periodicals - (1907-1915) (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - New York Times - Index - (1892-June 1915) - (1938-1941) (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Bulletin of The Public Affairs Information Service - 1915-1919, 1939 (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Municipal Accounting Reform. Municipal file, 1902-1905; The Accounting Historians Journal, 1987, Rochester, NY; Minneapolis, MN, 1902-1987 (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Congress of Accountants - (1904): Including: Letter to President Theodore Roosevelt; Letter to David R. Francis, Pres., Louisiana Purchase Exposition Commission, St. Louis, 1904 (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Nasmyth's File. PR visits, Philadelphia. Rochester, Syracuse, Auburn &Seneca Falls, NY., 1905 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Defalcation File, 1908 - 1909 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - - The McKesson Robbins case - (Accountancy 1955 and 1956) - and early correspondence, 1929-1956 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous Accountancy Articles: T. S. Adams: Principles of Excess Profits Taxation; Journal of Accountancy, Bulletins of American Institute of Accountants- 1944; Contemporary Accounting, a Refresher Course (American Inst. of Accountants) - 1945; The London Gazette of Jan. 1, 1850 - (1974); S. Paul Garner: Evolution of Cost Accounting to 1925; Precis for talk with John L. Carey re: his article - (Accountancy 1956); James H. Potts: Evolution of Municipal Accounting in the U.S. 1900-1935, 1944 - 1978 (Box 78, Folder 12)
      - G. O. May: articles, clippings, correspondence. Remarks at Union League Club (GOM) - 1914; S.E.C. Commission papers; article Long Term Liabilities and Capital Stock- 1945, Uniformity in Accounting' (Harvard Business Review) - 1938; The Profession of Accounting!' - 1911-1936; Influence of the Depression on Practice of Accounting - 1932; Memoirs and Accounting Thoughts- 1962, 1914 - 1962 (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - William B. Campbell death on June 22,1934 - news clippings, Jun-34 (Box 78, Folder 14)
      - International Investments: Historical Background; Foreign Investments in the American and Canadian West - 1870-1914; Foreign Investments in the U.S.A.; Industry and Empire; The Victorian Capital Market - 1914; America's Stake in International Investments - 1938 - (Cleona Lewis); Dictionary of Business Biography - 1860-1980; Article about Anthony Jaureguy (of Boston) - 1955; Dictionary of American Biography (Edwin Gay/Carter Glass) - 1946-1950; National Encyclopaedia. of American Biography (P. Brundage) - 1953-1959; The Export of Capital from Britain - 1870-1914, 1914 - 1974 (Box 78, Folder 15)
      - George O. May late correspondence and obituary. Includes May 22, 1961 - Mr. May's last correspondence - to Japan; May 23, 1961 - Letter to Haskins &Sells, 1945 - 1961 (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - Linda Edgerly Winthrop Group History Project: notes, indices, control forms and correspondence with records center (Box 78, Folder 17)
      - History of PW &Co. and Jones, Caesar &Co. - 1890-1901 (Parts 1 and 2) (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - Mary E. Curry Firm History: articles and correspondence. N.Y. Office Alumni Association - 1988; C. W. DeMond: PW in America - A History of a Public Accounting Firm- 1951; G.E. RichardsHistory of the Firm-The First Fifty Years, 1850-1900(British Firm)-1950; G. O. May -Correspondence, Leaves from my Life; Sixty Years of Avoiding Accounting Responsibility- J.B. Nimble-1950 (author unknown); List of Box/File contents: 1890-1909, 1944-1988 (Box 78, Folder 19)
      - Mary E. Curry Working notes from warehouse materials, 1987 - 1988 (Box 78, Folder 20)